Finally, the movie that proves that Justice isn't always Poetic, Jungle Fever
isn't always pretty, and Higher Learning can be a waste of time.
Don't Be a Menace to South Central While Drinking Your Juice in the
Hood is a comedy, crime film directed by Paris Barclay.
When Ashtray moves to South Central L.A.
to live with his father (who appears to be the same age he is) and grandmother (who likes to talk tough and smoke reefer), he falls in with his
gang-banging cousin Loc Dog, who along with the requisite pistols and Uzi carries a thermo-nuclear warhead for self-defense.
Will Ashtray be able to keep living the straight life?
Ashtray, played by Shawn Wayans.
Loc Dog, played by Marlon Wayans.
Dashiki, played by Tracey Cherelle Jones.
Preach, played by Chris Spencer.
Ashtray's Mother, played by Vivica A. Fox.
Ashtray's Father, played by Lahmard J. Tate.
Don't Be a Menace to South Central While Drinking Your Juice in the Hood (or simply Don't Be a Menace) is a 1996 American hood comedy film directed by Paris
Barclay in his feature directorial debut, written by and starring Shawn Wayans and Marlon Wayans along with contributions by Phil Beauman.
In the film, two cousins explore the surreal, comedic
world of South Central Los Angeles.
Don't Be a Menace spoofs several 1990s hood films, notably Menace II Society
(1993), South Central, Juice (both 1992), and Boyz n the Hood (1991).
It features cameos by actors from those films,
often parodying their original roles.
Produced by Keenen Ivory Wayans, it is the Wayans' second film to parody black film
culture and African-American society, after I'm Gonna Git You Sucka (1988).
Don't Be a Menace was theatrically released in the United
States on January 12, 1996, by Miramax Films.
It received mixed to negative reviews from critics
but has gained a cult following.
The film grossed $20.1 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of hip-hop, slang, date, gangster, cousin.
The tone is lighthearted.